var startBtn = document.querySelector(".start-button")
var startArea = document.querySelector(".start-area")
var quizArea = document.querySelector(".quiz-area")
var button1 = document.querySelector(".button-1")
var button2 = document.querySelector(".button-2")
var button3 = document.querySelector(".button-3")
var button4 = document.querySelector(".button-4")
var timeEl = document.querySelector("#timer")
var questionIndex = 0;
var timerName;
var time = 100;
// Creating object key/value pairs with questions, choices, and correct answer
var questions = [
	{
		question: "Which player owns the most number of championship rings in NBA history?",
		choices: ["Chris Mullin", "Michael Jordan", "Bill Russell", "Wilt Chamberlain"],
		correct: "Bill Russell"
	},
	{
		question: "Who is the only NBA player to average a triple-double?",
		choices: ["Magic Johnson", "Oscar Robertson", "Vince Carter", "Patrick Ewing"],
		correct: "Oscar Robertson"
	},
	{
		question: "Red Auerbach famously coached which NBA team?",
		choices: ["Boston Celtics", "New York Knicks", "Detroit Pistons", "Los Angeles Lakers"],
		correct: "Boston Celtics"
	},
	{
		question: "What was San Antonio Spur David Robinson's Nickname?",
		choices: ["Lieutenant", "Captain", "Admiral", "General"],
		correct: "Admiral"
	},
	{
		question: "Which of these players was the only one to attend college?",
		choices: ["Kobe Bryant", "LeBron James", "Kevin Garnett", "Kevin Durant"],
		correct: "Kevin Durant"
	},
	{
		question: "For what team did John Stockton play his entire career?",
		choices: ["Golden State Warriors", "Chicago Bulls", "Sacramento Kings", "Utah Jazz"],
		correct: "Utah Jazz"
	},
	{
		question: "What college team did Carmelo Anthony play for?",
		choices: ["Kentucky", "Syracuse", "Kansas", "Connecticut"],
		correct: "Syracuse"
	},
	{
		question: "Which player was NOT an overall number one pick in the NBA draft?",
		choices: ["Allen Iverson", "Michael Jordan", "Tim Duncan", "Dwight Howard"],
		correct: "Michael Jordan"
	},
	{
		question: "Which team beat the 1996 Chicago Bulls record 72 wins in a season?",
		choices: ["Miami Heat", "Los Angeles Lakers", "Golden State Warriors", "Dallas Mavericks"],
		correct: "Golden State Warriors"
	},
	{
		question: "Which NBA player famously scored 100 points in a single game?",
		choices: ["Wilt Chamberlain", "Kobe Bryant", "Stephen Curry", "Michael Jordan"],
		correct: "Wilt Chamberlain"
	}
]

// How to access elements of the question object
questions[0].question;
questions[0].choices[0]
questions[0].correct
console.log(questions.length - 1);

// When clicking start button, hide start area, and unhide quiz area
function start() {
	startArea.classList.add("hide")
	quizArea.classList.remove("hide")
	renderQuestion()
	timer()
}
// Call the timer and make it stop at zero
function timer() {
	timeEl.textContent = 'Time Remaining: ' + time + ' seconds';
	timerName = setInterval(function () {
		time--;
		timeEl.textContent = 'Time Remaining: ' + time + ' seconds';
		if (time === 0) {
			clearInterval(timerName)
		}
	}, 1000)
}

// Takes the current question and choice index and applies the question and choice pair to the text
function renderQuestion() {
	var currentQuestion = questions[questionIndex]
	document.querySelector(".question-text").innerText = currentQuestion.question
	button1.innerText = currentQuestion.choices[0]
	button2.innerText = currentQuestion.choices[1]
	button3.innerText = currentQuestion.choices[2]
	button4.innerText = currentQuestion.choices[3]
}

function saveInitials() {
	var history = JSON.parse(localStorage.getItem("initials")) || []
	var initials = prompt("Enter your initials: ")
	history.push({time, initials})
	localStorage.setItem("initials", JSON.stringify(history))
	window.location.reload()
}

function click(event) {
	console.log(event.target.textContent)
	console.log(this.textContent);

	// Check if the answer is incorrect and if it is wrong you are to deduct time from the game
	if (this.textContent !== questions[questionIndex].correct) {
		time -= 5;
		timeEl.textContent = 'Time. ' + time;
	}
	questionIndex++;

	console.log(questions[0]);
	console.log(questions.length);
	if (questionIndex === questions.length) {
		console.log('Game Over');
		quizArea.classList.add("hide")
		clearInterval(timerName)
		saveInitials()
	} else {
		renderQuestion()
	}
}

// Adding click event listeners to buttons
button1.addEventListener("click", click)
button2.addEventListener("click", click)
button3.addEventListener("click", click)
button4.addEventListener("click", click)

startBtn.addEventListener("click", start);

var items = JSON.parse(localStorage.getItem("initials")) || []
console.log(items);
items.forEach(element => {
	var item = document.createElement("span")
	item.innerText = element.initials + " " + element.time
	document.getElementById("initials").appendChild(item)
});